Md. Reazul Islam Razib

Corresponding address:

121/4A, Ibrahimpur Primary School Para, Ibrahimpur, Dhaka Cantonment,

Dhaka- 1206, Bangladesh. E-mail: reazul137@gmail.com

LinkedIn- https://www.linkedin.com/in/reazul-razib

Mobile: 01670750162

Career Objective:

To develop a flourishing career in the Supply Chain & Procurement sector by adding values and through inducing effective output based on my knowledge I've racked up in my academic life with experiences & professional skills acquiring in my professional life.

Key Qualities:

- ✓ Strong people management skills & able to build and lead a team to execute objective(s).
- ✓ Persuasive, collaborative, and adaptable in a diverse situation.
- ✓ Positive-minded, Self-motivated, and able to work independently under pressure.
- ✓ Robust analytical & communication skills & a critical thinker to solve the problem(s).

Experiences:

1. Inventory Management Officer

Paradise Sun Company Limited (June 2018-Present)

Responsibilities:

- ✓ Maintaining adequate stock of raw materials for smooth production and keeping a record of finished goods.
- ✓ Inputting data of daily raw material purchases & production in "Troyee" database software.
- ✓ Ensuring 5S mechanism for effective warehouse operations.
- ✓ Implementing ABC classification for optimizing picking time.
- ✓ Preparing purchase requisition and work orders.
- Preparing and monitoring manufacturing formulation provided by the nutritionist.
- ✓ Keeping an optimum supply chain function ensuring FIFO method.

2. Executive, Corporate Sales, and Service Center

Bikroy.com Limited (August 2015-December 2017)

Responsibilities:

- ✓ Selling corporate membership to prospective clients.
- ✓ Reviewing ads, emails, and identifying fraud advertisement posters.
- ✓ Keeping a one-to-one communication with clients for business purposes.

3. Student Counselor

Marks Consultants Ltd. (November 2013-May 2014)

Responsibilities:

- ✓ Counseling students who are interested to go abroad for higher study.
- ✓ Sourcing potential students and helping them through the full process.
- ✓ Preparing and collecting required documents to apply to the respective embassy.
- ✓ Communicating with prospective students.



Academic Credentials:

Degree	Institution	Concentration	Year	GPA
MBA	ASA University Bangladesh	Finance	2013	3.55
BBA	ASA University Bangladesh	Finance	2011	3.52
HSC	Dhaka City College	Commerce	2006	4.40
SSC	B. N. School & College, Chittagong	Commerce	2004	4.50

Extra-Curricular Activities:

✓ I have worked as a member of many organizing committees regarding cultural programs, sports, picnic, and many other events in my student life.

Training Summary:

Computer Skills:

✓ Import Export Training; a day-long training based on ✓ Proficient performer in Microsoft Office Import Export Business; from 'Import Export BD', Package, 'Troyee' database software.

Gulshan-1, Dhaka.

Personal Details:

Father's Name : Md. Salim Mollah

Mother's Name : Mrs. Salma Begum

Permanent Address : Vill.- Mugakati, P.S.- Uzirpur, Dist.- Barishal.

Date of Birth : December 11, 1989

Height : 5' 10"

Blood Group : B(+)

Marital Status : Married

I hereby declare that the information furnished above is true and to the best of my knowledge & belief.

Md. Reazul Islam

Reamel

Date: **20/05/2021**

References:

Md. Sirajul Karim Anwar Md. Shafiqul Islam Mamun

Factory Manager, Paradise Sun company Ltd. Manager, BRAC Bank Ltd.

Phone- 01770792311 Phone- 01755605244

Email- anwar@pscl-bd.com Email- shafiqulislam.mamun@bracbank.com